Leslie Turner Cartoons
Leslie Turner Cartoons
1966-1968
Turner, Leslie, b. 1899.
7 linear ft.
Original daily and Sunday cartoons from the newspaper comic strip Captain Easy.
2653509
Biographical History
Leslie H. Turner (1899-1988) was an American cartoonist. He was Roy Crane's assistant and eventual successor on the long-running newspaper comic strip Captain Easy.
Turner was born in Cisco, Texas in December of 1899. He served for a short time in the U.S. Army at the tail end of World War I and later attended Southern Methodist University, where he received his degree in 1922. Turner spent his early career doing freelance magazine illustration work in New York, placing his art in the top magazines of the time -- Judge, the Saturday Evening Post, Ladies' Home Journal and Boys' Life. In 1937, Turner was hired to assist on Roy Crane's popular newspaper adventure strip Wash Tubbs/Captain Easy*. Crane was content to leave the Sunday Captain Easy feature entirely to Turner, focusing his energy on the daily Wash Tubbs strips. In 1943, Crane signed on to produce a new strip for King Features Syndicate, Buz Sawyer. Turner inherited the daily and went on to draw both strips for many years, finally retiring at the end of the 1960s. His last Captain Easy strip appeared in January of 1970. Captain Easy continued its run until 1988.
*Crane's original daily feature was called "Wash Tubbs", but soon the popular Captain Easy character was spun-off to his own Sunday feature. After running separately for many years, the two strips both began to carry the title "Captain Easy" around 1949.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Leslie Turner Cartoons collection contains original daily cartoons and Sunday cartoons from the comic strip Captain Easy. Daily cartoon: traces of graphite, brush, pen and ink on Craftint board, approx. 6 x 18 1/4 in. Sunday cartoon: traces of graphite, pasteovers, brush, pen and ink on illustration board, approx. 17 3/4 x 26 in.
Arrangement of the Collection
Daily and Sunday cartoons are arranged separately in chronological order.
Related Material
See the
Roy Crane Papers
for additional material related to Wash Tubbs/Captain Easy. Please refer to for a complete listing of cartoon collections at the.
Subject and Genre Headings
Turner, Leslie, b. 1899.; Newspaper Enterprise Association.; Captain Easy (comic strip); Wash Tubbs (comic strip); Art -- Cartoonists; Adventure stories -- Comic books, strips, etc.; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Comic books, strips, etc. -- United States.; Cartoons (humorous images); Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Newspaper Enterprise Association, Inc., 1967-1969.
Inventory
- Captain Easy, 608
  Click here for detailed inventory.
  - Daily cartoons
    - Daily cartoons, 1966 Jan - 1966 Jun (Box 1)
    - Daily cartoons
    - Daily cartoons, 1966 Jul - 1966 Dec (Box 2)
    - Daily cartoons, 1967 Jan - 1967 Jun (Box 3)
    - Daily cartoons, 1967 Jul - 1967 Dec (Box 4)
    - Daily cartoons, 1968 Jan - 1968 Jun (Box 5)
    - Daily cartoons, 1968 Jul - 1968 Dec (Box 6)
  - Sunday cartoons
    - Sunday cartoons, 1966 Jan - 1966 Dec (Oversize 1)
    - Sunday cartoons, 1967 Jan - 1967 Dec (Oversize 2)
    - Sunday cartoons, 1968 Jan - 1968 Dec (Oversize 3)